唐山武馆
TANG SAN CLAN
师父 来了
Sifu, they're here
武林至尊
WITH RESPECT FROM WU LIN
谢谢 谢谢
Congratulations
在下 得各位英雄赏面谦让 得此薄名 真是愧不敢当
It's a humbling experience to have so many respectable heroes here to grace this occasion
庄大侠武功盖世 我们实在是佩服佩服
Your fighting skill has been an inspiration to us all
哪里 哪里 谢谢 谢谢
You're too kind
各位把匾抬上来
Present the board.
慢着
Hold on
庄三泰 我钟剑钧赶到了
Sam Tai, you didn't expect me to come to the celebration. Right?
原来是钟大侠驾到 失迎 失迎 请
It's Mr Chung. What a surprise? Please join us
我不是来喝酒的
I'm not here to socialise.
那么你
You're here for?
我要这块匾
I want this board
钟老前辈 这块匾是我师父比武得来的
Senior Chung, my Sifu won it in a Kung Fu tournament
比武 哼 有没有跟我比过啊
Kung Fu tournament? He hasn't fought with me
钟大侠 比武已经结束 你最好等下一届啦
Mr Chung, the tournament is finished. You'll have to wait for the next round
我已经赶到了 你不跟我过招
I'm already here, if you refuse to fight me
就算挂起这块匾都没有光彩
you haven't won the board honourably. Shame on you
你有什么了不起
What's so special about you?
放肆 不得对钟大侠如此无礼
Hold it Don't be rude to Senior Chung
钟兄 如果你认为小弟 不配挂这块匾 那你
Mr Chung, if you think that I'm not qualified to put this board up...
对啦 我就说你不配
That's my point. You're not qualified to put it up
除非你赢得了我三弹腿 这块匾就归你
If you can beat my Snapping Kick, this board is yours
你太过分了 如果你一定要比 我只好奉陪
You've gone too far. If you insist on fighting, I'm not going to back out
师父
Sifu
Sifu.
好功夫
Good Kung Fu
爹
Dad
赶快走吧
Stop or you'll kill him
不准打
Stop it
师父
Sifu...
让他把匾拿走
You can have the board
我看这个招牌也没有用了吧
You'll have no use for that board either
不公道 不公道
That's not fair, that's not fair
我已经认输了他还要打
I admitted defeat but he just wouldn't stop hitting me
浩云
How Yuen...
师父 我恐怕不行了
I'm afraid I won't last much longer
师娘师妹你要好好的照顾她们
You must take good care of Lan and Simo
我这口气死也不服
This is a grave injustice. I'll not die in peace
师父 你放心
Sifu, you'll be fine
我一定勤练武功 替你找回公道的
I'll train hard in my Kung Fu and take revenge for you
重振唐山武馆
The future of Tang San Clan...
全靠你了
...depends on you now
师父
Dad
Dad...
百胜道场
CHAMPION CLAN
各位请
This way, please.
雕虫小技 不足挂齿
That was easy, not worth mentioning
但是总算为地方争光
but we did make our presence felt
秋萍
Chou Ping
嗯
Yes...
所有人都到齐了 叫你娘出来
All the guests have arrived. Go and get your Mum
啊 知道了
Right away
娘 客人都到齐了 爹叫我来请你快点出去
Mum, all the guests are here. Dad is asking for you
娘
Mum...
爹 你快点来啊 快点来啊
Dad, come here quick. Come here quick
什么事
What's happened?
快点 快点 快点来嘛
Quick, come and see for yourself
快呀
Hurry up. Quick
快点
Please hurry up
您看
See for yourself
出了什么事
What's wrong?
妈妈…
Mum is...
剑钧吾夫
"My dear husband
你为了报复十八年前庄三泰 和我曾经相爱的私怨
"You've always been bothered by my relationship with Sam Tai 18 years ago
竟借比武毒手 打死三泰 良心何在
"I know you'll try any underhand methods to kill him "Where is your conscience?
我因爱君 故以死相劝
"Because I love you, I'll trade my life so God will have mercy on you
望君忍让为怀 行侠仗义
"I hope you'll be a better person in the future
我在九泉之下必当瞑目 秀秀绝笔
"My death will not have been in vain if you change "Your beloved wife."
大爷 我们是在此地干活的 我们真的不是故意的
Master, we're only working here. We're not doing anything wrong
大爷 您饶了我们吧
Please don't take it the wrong way
那只好怪你运气不好 谁叫你们看见的
It's your misfortune to have witnessed it
嗯哎 大爷
Master, don't. Please have mercy
快 快点去找 快去找
Listen up. Check around Search carefully.
有没有
Find anything?
没有
OK
到这边看看
Big Bro, the goods are here Let's have a look
老大 货在这儿呢
Fish it out, quick
快起货
Hurry up.
快
Got it.
上
Bring it ashore
哎哎 你们看 你们看
Hey can you see it?
那边有尸首 那边有尸首哎
- Is that a corpse? - It looks like it
哎 大家不要吵
Please be quiet
不要吵 咱们先把尸首捞起来
We'll bring it up and ask Master Chung what to do
然后呢再给转钟大爷看怎么办
What do you think?
住手
Stop
师兄弟过招怎么可以下毒手
You're sparring with your own man. No underhand tricks, please
师哥 对不起
I'm sorry, Big Brother
师父 南英青的功夫进步得真快啊
Sifu, Nam Sing's Kung Fu has improved a lot
我叫迟一步 你的腿早断了
If I hadn't stopped him in time, he'd have broken your leg
断了 怎么会了
Big Brother, is that true?
你再练三年也打不过我 不过我不会象你那样下毒手
You might beat me in 3 years But I won't use dirty tricks like you
人头猪脑 好好的想一想
What an idiot. Go away and think about it
你去练
Your turn.
是
Yes
放下
Put it down
钟大爷 您看看 再这样下去怎么办呢
Master, look at this
已经是第六个了
This is the sixth.
爹你看多可怕
Dad, it looks gross
这简直是无法无天 这种伤天害理的事 一定是魏家的人干的
Master, such immoral acts must have been committed by the Ngais
不要胡说 没有证据不能诬赖人家
Nonsense, you've no proof of that
我可以作证
I can be a witness
我亲眼看见的 是魏家的许胖子带人打死的
I saw the Ngai's Fatty Hui kill this guy
你愿意作证吗
You'll be the witness?
我绝对敢对质
I'll honour my words
太不象话了
He's crossed the line
方刚
Fong Kuo!
在
Sifu
你和南英青到魏家去一趟 叫许胖子来见我
Go to the Ngai's with Nam Sing Ask Fatty Hui to come and see me.
是
Yes
什么 找许胖子
They're looking for Fatty Hui?
嗯
Yes
不错 是我的人 二位有什么事
You're right, Fatty Hui is my man. Why are you looking for him?
他是杀人凶手 请你把他交出来
He's a murderer, hand him over
他杀人 谁看见了
He killed someone? Who witnessed that?
当然有人证 现在就是找他去对质
We've got a witness. We need him to come with us to explain
百忍道场 在地方上一向受人尊重
The Patience Clan is very respectable
而你们二位好像不太讲理
but you two are being unreasonable now
就算许胖子杀人 你也不能来找我呀
Even if Fatty Hui killed someone, you've no reason to come to me
他是你魏家的人
He's one of the Ngai's men
他已经不在这儿做了
He's no longer here
到哪去了
Where is he now?
不知道
I don't know.
我要你交人
Hand him over
放屁
Shut up,
这儿是什么地方 由得你来放肆
you're on our territory. You better watch what you say
你们想怎么样
What do you want to do?
二位不必生气 许胖子的确不在 此地大家何必伤和气了
Don't be angry. Fatty really isn't here We shouldn't spoil our relationship
等我找到了许胖子 可别怪我不客气
If we find Fatty Hui, don't blame us if it gets nasty It's your call.
你们看着办吧
That's right
哎哎
走
Let's go. See you
大哥 我看现在就把他们百忍道场给拆了
Big Bro, why don't we deal with Patience Clan now?
你懂什么 百忍道场在这很多名气
What do you know? Patience Clan is much respected around here
要除掉它 一定要名正言顺才行
If we want to get rid of them, we need to be clever about it
哎 对了 对了
That's right
时机未到 你们先别急呀
It's not the right time yet
等我跟小三子一切都安排好了 你还怕我们不去找他
We must be patient, we'll get them when we're fully prepared
我真担心我们到了那儿 找不到那个姓钟的
I hope that we can find Chung there
你放心好了 姓钟的在这里很有名望 一打听就打听到了
Don't worry, Chung is a well－known guy, we just have to ask around
就算他飞上天 我也要把他抓起来
Even if he can fly, I'll still find him
到了
We're there Move here.
哇哎哎 少爷 快来看 快来看
No I want to move here
你看那个妞长得好帅好棒啊
What a beautiful girl! Young Master, come and take a look Beautiful, I'll talk to her
小姐 你从远处来的吧 我来帮你拿好不好
Miss, your luggage must be heavy, can I help you?
不用
No need.
我又没问你
I wasn't asking you
我们是一块来的
We're together
你背的是什么
What's that you're carrying?
想看吗
You want to see?
想
Yes.
你不问问要看的代价是什么
Regardless of the price?
看看还要代价啊
What's the price?
怕你付不起
You can't afford it
你也不打听打听 我们魏家在这儿有什么付不起的
Don't you know? There's nothing the Ngais can't afford
你真付得起
You want to pay for it?
说多少
Tell me how much?
一条腿
A leg
太贵了吧
That's a bit expensive
没什么好讨价还价的
I'm not open to other offers
师娘 我们走
Simo, we can go now
什么玩意 看看就要一条腿
What is that? Costs a leg just to look at it?
哎 你们谁肯付啊
Who will do it?
少爷 我们付不起 太贵了
No, not me, not me
就你吧
You do it.
我 少爷 不行啊
No, I can't, my leg is...
对 对 对 去呀
Let's go, just do it
又有什么事
What now?
你不是说要一条腿我才能看你的宝贝东西吗 我带来了
Didn't you say it'd cost us a leg to look at it? We've got it.
少爷 少爷
Young Master,  I don't want to see it
是你要看吗
It's you who wants to see it?
哎
Yes
那不行
No deal.
怎么
Why?
谁看要谁的腿
The leg has to belong to the person who wants to see it
还要不要看
You really want to see it?
好 有种 改天再看
Good on you. We'll see it another day
走
Let's go.
浩云 我们出门在外什么事都要忍耐
How Yuen. This is not our territory, you should be more tolerant
这不能怪师哥 那家伙实在讨厌
Mum, you can't blame him. Those guys are so annoying
妈 我们现在上哪
Mum, where should we go now?
当然是直奔百胜道场
Let's go to the Champion Clan's
不用忙 我们先找个地方住下来
There's no rush. We should look for a place to stay
明天是你师父三周年忌期
Tomorrow is the third anniversary of your Sifu's death
我想上庙烧个香 既然来了也不在乎多呆个一两天
I want to go to the temple to make an offering Since we're here, let's stay a few days.
是
Yes, Simo
冥府殿
MING FU TEMPLE
师哥 你不舒服啊
How Yuen. Not feeling well?
那你干什么 有心事
What are you doing? Something's bothering you?
我有什么心事
Nothing is bothering me
你是不是怕
Are you afraid?
怕
Afraid?
为了师父的仇恨 为了唐山门的名誉
To avenge the death of Sifu, to avenge the name of Tang San Clan
我的心里永远没有怕字
I've never been afraid in my life
那为什么你来了此地之后态度跟以前完全变了
Why has your attitude changed so much since we arrived here?
如果你真的怕 现在回去还来得及
If you're afraid, it's not too late to turn back
你误会了 我是有心事 我担心你跟师娘
You've misunderstood. I'm actually worried about
是不是你认为我们是你的累赘
Simo's and your well－being Have we caused you any inconvenience?
那你更误会了
That's an even worse misunderstanding!
我是怕万一输给钟剑钧 以后谁来照顾你们
My worry is, if I'm defeated by Chung, who'll look after you two?
那你不用担心 我们会自己照顾自己
You needn't worry, we'll look after ourselves
总之你千万不能泄气
You shouldn't be demoralised
我不会泄气 你照顾师娘 我去逛逛
I'm not demoralised. Look after Simo, I'll take a walk
少爷 那小子又来了
Young Master, that chap is here
你是从外地来的
Are you from another town?
是的
Yes
到我们这儿干什么
Why are you here?
我的事不劳过问
That's my business
那入境随俗 进庙得有个规矩
You must follow the rules and regulations if you want to come here
什么规矩
What are the rules and regulations?
打这儿进去
To come in. You've to go through here
出去要从这儿出去
To go out, you've to go through here
谁定的规矩
Who approved the rules and regulations?
本少爷
Me
又是你
You again.
你是要进去呢 还是要出去
You want to come in or go out?
我无意结怨也不愿受辱
I've no intention to make enemies and don't wish to be humiliated
那么交个朋友呢
Let's be friends.
不交
Friends?
上
Get him.
慢着
Don't move Stop
姓魏的 你太过分了
Ngai, you're being ruthless
管闲事的来了
Look who's here
不许你们欺负人 放开他
I won't let you bully anyone here. Let him go
关你什么事 我又没有欺负你
That's none of your business? I wasn't bullying you
我偏要管
I'll take it as my business.
你管得太多了
I won't let you
让他走
Let him go.
你说就行了
Why should I listen to you?
一个刚从外地来的人又没有得罪你 你凭什么要欺负人家
He's just arrived in our town and hasn't offended you. Why must you bully him?
你要打抱不平 小白脸你看上了
You're standing up against injustice? You've fallen for him
你敢欺负你姑奶奶
You want to bully me too? Friend, you can go now
朋友 你快走
Go, get out of here.
走啊 快走 走了
Get him
小子 可有死过
Don't you dare get involved
上
Fight.
那边
They're there
走 走 走
Let's go. Let's go
刚才多谢你帮忙 我叫钟秋萍 请问你贵姓啊
Thanks for your help. I'm Chung Chou Ping What is your name?
不是冤家就是债主 明儿见
You can call me either enemy or creditor See you tomorrow
他说什么呀 我都听不懂
What did he say? I don't understand
为什么要明天见
Why will he see me tomorrow?
我懂 回去告诉师父
I know. Let's go and inform Sifu
师父
Sifu
Sifu.
弟子们到齐了
All the trainees are here
他们既然到了这 一定会来找我的
If they're here, they'll be looking for me
所以我召集你们来 有话要交代
I assembled all of you here to do something for me
爹 他还跟我说明天见
Dad, he said he'd see me tomorrow
那他一定明天来
He'll definitely come tomorrow
如果他们来了 你们不准难为他们
If they're here, I don't want you lot to be rude to them
是
OK
师父 我不明白您的意思
Sifu, I don't know what you mean
师弟
你不用问 我怎么说你怎么做
Just do what you're told. No questions asked
就算他们动手打你们 你们都不准还手
Even if they hit you, you're not to retaliate
爹 为什么呢 难道我们怕他吗
Dad, why? Are you afraid of them?
我不是怕他们 是我欠了他们
I'm not afraid of them but I did wrong them
大哥 我查清楚了 他是从唐山来的 叫唐浩云
Big Bro, I've checked him out. He's from Tang San Clan His name is Tang How Yuen.
唐山
Tang San Clan?
小三子告诉我 几年前钟老头打伤了庄三泰
A few years back, Chung defeated Sam Tai badly in a fight
拆了唐山武馆的招牌 庄三泰气愤而死
He also broke the Tang San Clan sign board
他这次来 八成是报仇来的
Sam Tai died from the trauma How Yuen must be here for revenge
怪不得那小子一身好功夫 他不是猛龙不过江
No wonder his Kung Fu is so good He comes fully prepared
那就好了 咱们隔山观虎斗 在这儿瞧热闹
Good news for us, we can stand back and see them injure each other
他身手真的那么好
Is his Kung Fu that good?
我看呀 比二哥还好
He's better than Second Brother
我们五个人打他一个 除了挨打 想摸他一下真是门都没有
The five of us not only got beaten up, we couldn't even touch him
真的这么厉害吗 我明天要会会他
Is he that good? I want to challenge him now
何必去斗那个气呢
There's no need for that
想办法收买他 去对付钟老头 那不是更好吗
Isn't it better to get him on our side to fight that old man for us?
老三 交给你去办
Sun. I'll leave this to you
那还不容易 坏招我多的是
No problem. I'm the crafty one here
这件事您放心 交给我啦
I'll convince him to join forces with us
师哥 你怎么啦
How Yuen. What are you doing?
我找到了我们要找的人
I've found our enemy
浩云
How Yuen.
那你还在想什么 我们不是为结仇而来 只想讨个公道回去
What are you waiting for? We're not here for revenge, we just want some justification
我知道 我是在考虑您跟师妹
I know, but I'm worried about you and Lan
我们不是问题
Don't let us get in the way
我不是跟你讲过吗 不要担心我们
Didn't I tell you not to worry about us?
只要你把钟老头打败了 替爹报了仇 妈就开心
As long as you beat that old man in a fight to avenge dad Simo will be contented
浩云 我要真能看到你 为师门争回这口气
How Yuen. Only if I witness that old man pay for his crime
我死也瞑目了
will I be able to die in peace
您言重了 替师父报仇 是我的责任
Don't say that, to avenge Sifu is my responsibility
什么时候去找他 您吩咐
Just tell me when
好 明天天一亮就去找他
In the morning.
是
Yes
就是这儿
Simo, we're here
百忍道场
PATIENCE CLAN
请你通报一下
Can you announce our visit?
请
This way, please
请你通报一下
Can you announce our visit?
请
This way, please
庄夫人 请坐
Madam, please be seated
难得你还记得我
I'm surprised you still remember me
虽然事隔多年 我知道你们一定会来的
The incident might have happened years ago, but I knew you'd come
那你该知道我们为什么而来
You know why we're here?
知道
I know
你也应该知道我们要的是什么
You must know what we want
当然 我更加知道
Of course. I know that very well
还我们
Return it, then.
我一定还的
I will
什么时候
When?
三天后
In three days
为什么
Why?
因为那一天是 我难忘的日子
That's a special day for me
希望在那一天 我们能做了断
I want to settle our grievances on that day, once and for all
你们到底想怎么样 我们百忍堂决不会怕你们的
What else do you want? The Patience Clan is not afraid of you
秋萍 不要多讲
Chou Ping, don't be rude
你们几位可以宽限我三天吗
Can you give me three more days?
你讲话算数
You'll honour your words?
一言为定
I promise
在什么地方
Where?
就在这里
Here
好 准时拜访
OK, we'll come again
师娘 我们走
Simo, let's go
你为什么不坐下来 走来走去干什么
Have a seat. Why are you pacing around?
我在想他们为什么 约我们三天之后了
I'm wondering why they asked for three more days
我也觉得很奇怪 他们人这么多 你真要小心啊
It puzzles me too We're outnumbered, you've got to be careful
我不会怕他们的
I'm not afraid of them
反正这次来我不能要回唐山门的面子 我是不会回去的
I won't quit until I reinstate Tang San Clan's reputation
是 师娘
It's Simo
师娘 妈
Simo, what is it?
我好痛啊
It hurts, it really hurts
师娘 你怎么啦
Simo, what happened?
我 我 我这里好痛啊
I've got a pain here
怎么会突然痛了
All of a sudden?
我也不知道我喝了一杯茶
I don't know why
一会就痛起来了
but I felt the pain after drinking that tea
有人来过没有
Has anyone been here?
我不知道
I don't know
好像有点脚步声 我以为是你
but I did hear footsteps I thought it was you two.
我才出去一会 不会有人进来
We went out earlier, it couldn't have been
师哥 你的手 我替你包起来
I'll dress the wound for you
不要紧 你照顾师娘 我擦点药就好
Don't bother. I'll just apply some lotion
贵姓
Who are you?
百忍道场大弟子 方刚
The most senior student of Patience Clan. Fong Kong
半夜三更的 你来干什么
What are you doing here in the middle of the night?
我来问你我师父 到底欠了你什么
I want to know what my Sifu owes you?
三年前 你不是亲眼看见的吗
Didn't you see it three years ago?
那只怪你们唐山 武学技不如人
That's only because the Tang San Clan's Kung Fu is lousy
所以我这次来要为师门讨回公道
That's why I'm here to to reinstate our name fairly
怎么样才算公道
What do you consider fair?
用我们唐山拳会他的三弹腿
To pit my Tang San Fist against your Snapping Kicks
要是你输了呢
What if you lose?
任凭处置 要是我赢呢
Do what you want with me What if I win?
你想怎么样
What do you want?
问你师父去
Go and ask your Sifu
在问我师父前 先问问我
Before going to my Sifu, you'll need my permission
想打架 外面去
If you want to fight, let's go outside
这算不算问过你
Do I get your permission now?
怎么吃了亏回来了
So? Lost the fight?
师父 你怎么知道的
Sifu, how do you know?
你有什么可以瞒得过我
You can't hide anything from me
为什么不听我的话
Why didn't you listen to me?
师父 你是以武技打败庄三泰 我们并没有错啊
Sifu, you beat Sam Tai fairly. What's wrong with that?
为什么你老是觉得欠他的一样 怕他怕成这个样子
Why do you have to give in to their claims? Why are you afraid of them?
你不会明白 是我欠他的
It's my duty to them
就算你欠他的 弟子有责任替师父还债
Whatever you owe them, I'm obliged to repay them
你刚才还没让他打够吗
Didn't you get enough earlier?
所以请师父教弟子绝技三弹腿 弟子一定要跟他去拼
That's why I'd like to ask you, Sifu, to teach me the Snapping Kicks I want to fight him to the end
为什么你总是让我教你三弹腿呢
Why are you so interested in Snapping Kicks?
唐浩云不是猛龙不过江
Tang How Yuen won't be here unless he's fully prepared
就算我的三弹腿 也未必打得过他
The Snapping Kicks might be of no threat to him
为什么我不如他 为什么我不如他
Why can't I match up to him? Why?
这种私人的恩怨何必放在心上
We shouldn't let these personal matters affect us
现在最重要的是找出魏友危害地方的证据 将许胖子找出来
The most important thing now is to look for evidence against the Ngais We must find Fatty Hui
方刚 如果你诚心替师父做事 就将许胖子找出来
If you want to be of help to Sifu, go and find Fatty Hui
你办得到吗
Can you do it?
我办得到 我一定找他出来
Definitely. I'll find him
怎么没人呢
Why is there no one here?
不用怕 就算有埋伏 也不用怕他们
We've nothing to worry about
我唐浩云来了
I, Tang How Yuen. Am here
请
This way, please
This way
请
Over there
爹 他们已经到了
Dad, they're here.
请他们进来
Show them in
请
Please go in
请进
Come in. Please
秋萍 你出去
Chou Ping, you can go now
爹
Dad.
出去
Go now
是
OK
把门关上
Close the door.
是
OK
钟剑钧 你把我们带到这里来 好像不是个理想的地方
Chung, this doesn't look like an ideal place to settle our score
这是一个可以了断过节的场所
This is the best place to let bygones be bygones
今日是我亡妻 三周年的忌日
Today is the third anniversary of my wife's death
对我来讲是个很重大的日子
It's an important date to me
我认为今日在我亡妻的灵前
Right here at the shrine of my late wife
了断我们之间的过节 是一个很恰当的地方 你们想怎么样
is the best place to settle our score What do you think?
今天我们要把账总算一下
We have to settle all our grievances today
首先 你给我把这个还原
For a start, you've got to restore this
匾已破 叫我怎么样还原
The board is already broken. How can I restore it?
唐山武馆
TANG SAN CLAN
请你们看看那个箱子
Please open the chest there
我这样做也不能减轻我内心的惭愧
I did that to alleviate the remorse I feel
那 那条腿
And the leg?
我当年气盛铸成大错
I'd been blinded by the lure of power and done you wrong
内疚于心
I deeply regret what I've done
今日见到你们 心里反为踏实了
Seeing you today makes me feel much better
你想用苦肉计博取我们的同情
You're using tricks to get our compassion
我钟剑钧难道不应该奉上金匾一方 自断一腿
I've presented you with a golden board and my own leg as an apology
向九泉之下的人谢罪吗
Is that not enough?
我将百胜门的胜字改为忍字
I've also changed my clan's name from Champion to Patience
就是要等今日
All just for today
你们想怎么样处置我 就动手吧
I'll pay for my mistake Go ahead
住手
Stop
钟剑钧 我们之间的过节算了
Chung, that's all I need to know. We've settled our score
算了 师娘 我们千里迢迢到这里来
Is that it? Simo, we've waited all this time for today
算了
Enough
师哥 我也想报杀父之仇
How Yuen. I want to avenge my father too
可是你能欺负一个不还手的残废吗
But, how could you lay hands on someone who can't fight back?
不公道
That's not fair.
That's not fair
这消息靠得住吗
Is the news reliable?
是小三子亲口告诉我的
I heard it from Sun
他们的过节一了 姓唐的不是可以回唐山了吗
Is How Yuen going to leave after this?
您放心 他走不了的
Don't worry, he won't leave
为什么
Why?
老大 我这个赛孔明
Big Bro, I've already
是早有妙计巧安排的
set other plans in motion that will benefit us
你别跟我酸溜溜的 到底搞什么鬼
What have you done now?
我用的是借刀杀人之计
Practising the art of manipulation
还要他自己送上门来 姓唐的是三国的赵云
Tang How Yuen is rumoured to be one of the best fighters around
这一员猛将 很快的就会来给你效命的啦
He'll soon be of service to you
大夫 好点了吗
Doctor, is she OK?
我看这个方子不用开了
No medicine can help her now
怎么没得治了
What do you mean?
她得的是怪病 这种普通药吃多了也没有用
She has a strange disease. None of the medicine works on her
大夫 麻烦你勉为其难再开个方子吧
Doctor, please give my mum another course of medicine
我开方子也没有用啊
As I've said, no medicine seems to work on her
除非能求得魏府的家传秘方 也许有救
Unless you can get hold of the secret medicine from the Ngais. That might work
大夫 请你帮忙去求一求 多少钱我都给
Doctor, please help us. Money is not a problem
哎 人家是大财主 在乎钱吗
The Ngais are very wealthy, they don't need your money
你带我去求一求 只要能治好师娘的病 为他作牛作马都行
Please bring me to them, I'll do anything to help Simo recover
好 我可以带你去试试
OK, I'll try my best
你有什么事吗
Tang How Yuen. Can I help you?
请你通报一身声 我要见你们魏大爷
I'm here to see Master Ngai
您还用通报啊 请进 请进
We're expecting you. This way
魏大爷 唐师父来见您
Master Ngai, Sifu Tang is here to see you
什么风把你吹来的 请进 请进
What a surprise. This way, please
坐
Have a seat.
谢谢魏大爷的药 这点薄礼
Thank you for the medicine Something for you.
你还这么客气干什么 坐 坐
You're too polite Please have a seat
怎么 药丸还有效吗
Was the medicine effective?
有效 一吃心口就不痛了
Yes, the pain in the chest is gone now
那就好 这药是魏家的祖传秘方 我很少送给人的
Great, the medicine has been passed down for generations I don't normally give it away
是 我今天来就是想请您多给一点
I understand but I really do need more of it
当然不能说是跟您买了 但是 我得意思意思 请您出个价钱
Medicine like that should be priceless but I hope you can name a token price so I can get more of it
不是钱的问题
Money is not a problem but we do have limited stock
我也只剩这么多 我怕你们回到唐山病又发了怎么办
What if she falls sick again after you return to Tang San
真是的 路又那么远
You've a point. It's a long journey too
我当然不能把秘方送给你
I'm sorry but I can't give you the recipe
我倒有个两全的办法
I've got a good idea. You can stay here for a while
你们先暂时住在这儿 你们的生活由我照看
I'll pay for your upkeep What do you think?
我知道你功夫不错 而我这儿呢也正缺人手
I know that your Kung Fu is not bad It just so happens that I need some help too
你要明白 我大哥一生爱才他是提拔你的
Big Bro likes to nurture raw talents like yours
我们赶着回唐山 我师娘想家
We want to return to Tang San as soon as we can. Simo is homesick
病了怎么走啊
She's too ill to walk
你们安心住下去 等你师娘病好了再走 我绝不留你们
You're welcome to stay here until she's fully recovered
这是我大哥一番好意呀 你就交个朋友啦
Big Bro has a kind heart. He just wants to be friends
那你们要我做什么呢
What can I do for you in return?
对付百忍道场 他们人多功夫好 一直欺负我们
Help us to defeat the Patience Clan. They've been bullying us
希望以后你能主持公道
We hope that you'll help us gain justice
还有 听说你是因为钟老头是个残废而不忍下手
We heard that you let Chung go because he's handicapped
其实 他那条腿不是因为你们断的
He didn't chop off his leg for you
他知道他打不过你 故意装成可怜的样子 使你就无法下手
He knows that he can't beat you so he tried to get your sympathy
哎呀 你上当了
You've fallen for his dirty trick
药丸只剩这么点了 你先带回去 我立刻派人去给你配
That's all the medicine I have now Take this first, I'll get my man to make more
够了
Enough
今天看在唐师父的面子 只要你一条腿
Because of Sifu Tang, we'll only break one of your legs today
明天你们四兄弟不把茶园的地契送到魏家
Bring your lease contract to the Ngais tomorrow
就要你们的命
or you won't live
听到没有
to see another day
唐师父 请
Sifu Tang, our business here is done
限你们三天搬离此地
We want you to be gone in three days
你们这样无法无天 我们要去找钟老爷评评理
You guys are ruthless. I'll report this to Master Chung
就是要你们去
That's what we want
浩云 你慢点走
How Yuen. Please wait
我是故意在这儿等你的
I've been waiting for you
什么事
What can I do for you?
我实在不敢相信 你在跟魏家做事
I can't believe you're working for the Ngais now
不错 我是在替他做事
I'm definitely working for the Ngais
你不要再继续做下去
You've got to stop.
还要
I won't
你要是不了解魏苍龙的为人 我可以告诉你
If you want to know more about the Ngais, I can tell you
不必
No need
他是专门跟我们百忍堂为敌的
He's the Patience Clan's arch enemy
我无可选择
I've no other choice
最好你不要去惹他
You shouldn't provoke him in the future
我真是不明白我们之间还有什么仇怨呢
I don't understand, I thought we'd settled all our scores
你真的想知道
Do you really want to know?
当然啦
Of course
很简单 我师父已经死啦
It's simple. My Sifu is dead
你爹虽然断了一条腿 还活着
and even though your dad has lost a leg, he's still alive
明白了吧
Get it now?
怪不得你不回唐山 怪不得你要替魏家做事
No wonder you've not gone back to Tang San No wonder you work for the Ngais
我爹跟我们说过很多次 不许我们恨你
My dad always asks us not to hate you
我一直认为 你是光明正大的男子汉
I thought you were a man of your word
想不到你是 我恨你 恨你
But you're not. I hate you, I hate you
是你
It's you.
我恨死你
I'll kill you
南英青
Stop fighting
不要再打了 不要打了
Stop fighting, stop fighting
不要打了 不要打了 你们不要再打了
Stop, you two stop fighting
你还不快点走
Go now
师娘 这是您喜欢吃的果子 这两块衣料是买给你的
Simo, your favourite cake This fabric is for you
这个颜色我喜欢
I like the colour. It's nice
师娘 您的药
Simo, more medicine
正好 药昨天我刚刚吃完了
I've just finished mine as well
吃完了 上次给的一百粒没有几天吗
That's quick, I gave you a hundred tablets last time
我也不知道 以前每次吃三颗就不痛了 现在啊 吃六颗都止不住
I've increased the dosage from three to six tablets to relieve the pain
妈 你怎么没告诉我
Mum, why didn't you tell me?
我的病 已经把你们都烦死了
My illness has troubled you two enough So what if I need to take more medicine?
说来干什么 多吃就多吃点 好啦 只要不痛就是了嘛
As long as I'm not in pain. There's no reason to tell you
越吃越多 这也不是个办法啊
Having to increase your dosage that's not an ideal solution
浩云 魏财主真是个好人
How Yuen. Ngai is really a good guy
可是我常常这样麻烦人家也不是个事
We've troubled them long enough
能不能这样 求他把方子给我们 我们自己去配就好了
Why don't we ask them for the recipe and make the medicine when we're back home?
我每次问他拿这个药都不容易 秘方他不肯给
He's refused me a number of times I don't understand why?
那怎么办呢 为了这个病 我们几时才能回唐山了
What can we do? My illness has kept us here When can we return to Tang San?
师娘 您放心 我在帮他们做事 药他一定会给我的
Don't worry, Simo I'm working for them now, we'll have no problem getting the medicine
我总会想办法尽快回唐山的
I'll think of a way to get us back to Tang San as soon as possible
我先回房了
I'll go and rest now.
唐浩云 唐浩云
Tang How Yuen
这么大声叫我 什么事啊
You don't need to shout. What is it?
我们大哥找你
Big Bro's looking for you
天都黑了
It's late now.
大概有要紧的事情吧
It's important
这个
Let's see...
走啊
Come on Mum,
妈 你有没有看出来 师哥心里好像有什么话说不出来
have you noticed? How Yuen seems to be hiding something
自从你爹死了之后 多亏了他
He's been a great help since your dad died
就算我亲生的儿子 也不会待我们这么好的
He treats me better than any son treats their mother
什么事啊
What's up?
哥哥 你上哪儿去呀
Brother, where are you going?
你睡觉 我们就回来
Sleep tight, we'll be back soon
我查到了今天魏家走私的地方 我们去抓去
I know where the Ngais are loading their stuff, let's catch them
那还不告诉师父
Let's tell Sifu
不用告诉他老人家 又要说忍啊忍啊不许干 我们先干了再说
If we tell him, he'll ask us to be patient We'll inform him later.
就在前面 小心点
This way
快
Hurry up
Quickly!
站住
Don't move
你们在干什么 今天 总算给我们抓到了
What are you doing? Finally got caught in the act?
本少爷要干什么就干什么 你管得着吗 上
I'll do what I want, it's none of your business
走
Let's go
不准走
Let's split up
搜
Search
这么晚了还有什么事
It's getting late, what do you want?
今晚上有一批贷要在这儿交 大哥怕有意外所以叫你来看看
We've got a transaction tonight Big Bro wants you here to make sure nothing goes wrong
这是谁家的小孩 睡在这个地方
It's too late for a kid to be lying here
快
Let's look there
是小喜子 小喜子
Kiddo, kiddo!
小喜子
Kiddo!
唐浩云
Tang How Yuen. You're despicable
不是人 你是畜生 我们百忍道场跟你有什么仇
What do you have against the Patience Clan now?
连个小孩子你都下得了手
How could you hurt a child?
我
I...
你听我说
Let me explain.
还有什么说的
What's there to explain?
到了现在你们还要狠
How dare you?
出来
Get them
两位 我替你们找的坟地不错吧
Isn't this a good location to rest in peace?
唐浩云 大哥叫你到这儿来 就是干这件事
Tang How Yuen. Big Bro wants you here to do this
把他们两个干掉
Kill them.
我不干
No way
你不干
Why not?
我唐浩云做事一向光明磊落
I think it's dishonourable
你不干 是真的
You really won't do it?
来啊 把他们两干掉
Guys, kill them.
不许动
Stop
放他们走
Let them go
他们好不容易才中了我的计 放他们走 大哥怪起来谁负责
We don't often get a chance like this If we let them go, who will answer to Big Bro?
我负责 谁不怕死尽管动手
Me, whoever touches them will die at my hands
你
You...
二位请吧
You two can go. -
师姐
Senior, I'm convinced now
对不起 师弟 没有打痛你吧
I hope I didn't hurt you
没有
No
小喜子 怎么回事 是谁干的
Kiddo. What happened? Who did it?
是谁干的
Tell me
到底是谁干的
Tell me who did it.
你说话 你怎么不说话
Why won't you tell me?
我亲眼看见是姓唐的
I saw Tang do it. I saw Tang do it
我亲眼看见姓唐的干的 我为什么打不过他
I want to take revenge but I can't beat him
我要报这个仇
I'm useless.
这是不可能的事
I don't believe it
真的是他干的
Are you sure it was him?
是啊
It was him
爹
Dad...
你们想干什么
What do you want?
说不说 许胖子躲在什么地方
Spit it out. Where's Fatty Hui hiding?
我说 我说
I'll tell you
咱们一块去的
Listen up, brother.
是吗
What is it?
我告诉你昨晚上我泡了个妞 那真是棒级了
Let me tell you something. I met a beautiful girl last night
看她年龄顶多十八九岁 那脸蛋是细皮白肉的
While we were haggling over the price, I touched her and she was ecstatic
不要再打了 我们要留个活口
Stop, keep him for questioning
姓魏的 你回去告诉你们大哥
Hey, go and tell your Big Bro
我们回去问清楚了 再来找他算账
we'll come for him after we question this one
好 现在是算账的时候了
Now is the time to get even
我一直叫大家忍耐 现在忍无可忍
I've always told you guys to be patient but everything has its limit
既然许胖子都招出来了 姓魏的罪大恶极
Since Fatty Hui's confession. We can confirm that the biggest villain is Ngai
今天我要跟他算清这笔账
I'll make sure he pays for it
方刚 拉许胖子出来
Go get Fatty Hui.
是
Yes
秋萍 把我的手杖拿来
Chou Ping, get my crutch
爹 你要手杖干什么
Dad, what do you need that for?
我要亲自去见姓魏的
I want to go and see Ngai
不好 万一动起手来了
Don't go. What if he gets physical?
我还有一条腿 去拿啊
I still have one leg. Go and get it
哦
OK, then
许胖子 起来 我们要送你回去了
Fatty Hui, get up. We're sending you home now
怎么 你想赖着不走啊
What now? Don't want to go?
师父 出了事啦 许胖子被人暗杀了
Sifu, bad news. Fatty Hui has been killed
是谁干的 现在连证人都没有了 这怎么办了
Now we've lost our main witness. What shall we do now?
你们说是谁干的
Any idea who did it?
师父 完了
Sifu, what shall we do now?
这一次我们跟魏家的账又不能算了
We can't get even with the Ngais now
何止不能算
That's not the worst of it
魏家的人死在我们这儿 他们决不会罢休的
The Ngai's man died in our custody. They will hold us responsible
我看很麻烦
We're in real trouble
许胖子死啦 谁说的
Fatty Hui's been killed? Who told you?
小三子亲眼看见的
Sun saw it himself
把我的人抓了去随随便便的杀了
They held our man in custody but couldn't even protect him
浩云 你说他们是不是欺人太甚
How Yuen. Don't you think they're big bullies?
你别动气 问问清楚再说
You shouldn't be too upset until you know the truth
现在你没第二条路可走 浩云 我们要他们交出许胖子来
There's no other way now. How Yuen. Go and claim Fatty Hui's body
交不出来的话 你替我把百忍道场给拆掉
Trash Patience Clan's place after that
这件事我绝对不能做
That's something I won't do
你不做 他们认为你杀死小喜子 早晚也不会放过你
You won't do it? They thought you killed Kiddo, they'll come for you next
你在场最清楚了 小喜子不是我杀的
We all know very well that I didn't kill Kiddo
我可以跟他们解释
You can explain that to them
你用嘴巴说 他们就相信你了吗
You think they'll trust what you say?
他们相信不相信都不要紧 这件事我还是不做
I don't care but I'll not do it
你想一想 你本来是替师父报仇来的
Think about it, you're working for the Ngais
这是天公地道的 江湖上谁也不能说你不是
It's only right that you protect the Ngai's interests
浩云 我魏苍龙咽不下这口气
How Yuen. I won't let this matter rest
你只要替我办妥了这件事 我把秘方送给你 你随时回唐山
If you do this for me, I'll give you the recipe for the medicine You can return to Tang San after that
如果许胖子没有死呢
What if Fatty Hui's still alive?
那最好了 大家都没事 我药方也一样送给你
That's even better. No one loses I'll still give you the recipe
什么事啊
Can I help you?
庄小姐住哪间房
Which room is Lan in?
那间
That one.
谢谢
Thank you
我有一点事情 可以跟你谈谈吗
I've something to talk to you about
庄伯母
Auntie Zhong.
是你呀 你怎么来了
It's you. Can I help?
有什么话你可以说了
What do you want?
庄姑娘 我可是诚心诚意来的
Lan. I don't have any bad intentions...
谁相信你
Cut the crap
你怎么可以这样讲话呢 请坐
Don't be rude. Please be seated
先喝杯热茶
Have some hot tea.
你们两位可知道 唐浩云在外边做些什么事吗
Do you know what How Yuen's been up to recently?
知道 他在魏财主家里做事
We know. He's doing some manual work for Ngai
不错 可是他做的都是坏事
He's definitely working for the Ngais but what he's doing is illegal
坏事
Illegal?
你不要胡说 我师哥不是这种人
Nonsense. How Yuen is not like that The Ngai brothers are the big bullies here
魏家四虎是这里的恶霸 他做了他们的帮凶鱼肉百姓
How Yuen is helping them to oppress the villagers
我真替他不值
I think he's been misled
我一点都不知道啊
I really don't know about this.
不会吧
What do you think?
不会
It can't be
就算我师哥做坏事也与你无关 为什么你要来告诉我们
Even if it's true, it's none of your business What's your motive for telling us this?
我早就猜到你们两位还不知道
I know you're in the dark about this
所以特地来警告 你们早点回唐山去吧
My advice to you is to return to Tang San quick
我们回不回唐山要听你的吗
When we return to Tang San has nothing to do with you
姓魏的心狠手辣 唐浩云是一个老实人 斗不过他们的
The Ngais are too shady for a decent guy like How Yuen They'll exploit him
不要把他的命丢在这儿
if he's not careful
再见
See you
钟姑娘
Miss Chung,
我只要跟你说一句话
I've got something to tell you
什么话
What is it?
小喜子的事不是我做的
I didn't kill your brother
你这是干什么 良心惭愧
How could you do it? Haven't you got a conscience?
你在外面做的坏事我全都知道 我去告诉娘去
I know you've been involved in illegal activities I'll tell Mum.
师妹
Please don't
拿开你的脏手
Don't touch me
我求求你别告诉师娘
Please don't tell Simo
我要
I'll tell her.
师妹
Don't
你为什么要做那些见不得人的事 为什么
Why did you get involved in illegal activities?
为什么
Why did you do it?
我为了师娘
I did it for Simo
我只要那些药丸治好师娘的病
I need their medicine for Simo's illness
我只要师娘颐养天年 不再受疼痛之苦
If it stops Simo having to go through any pain
我什么事都肯做
I'm willing to do anything
哪怕是不仁不义的事
Even if it's unethical
我从小没爹没娘
I lost my parents when I was a kid
全靠师娘抚养我长大
It's Simo who took care of me
全靠师父教养我成人
It's Sifu who taught me the ways of life
我来不及报答师父的恩 也要全心全意报答师娘
Since I can't repay Sifu, I'll do all I can to repay Simo
梦兰 师娘年事已高 报恩之日无多
Lan. I don't have much time left to repay Simo
师哥
Brother
我只为了尽人子之孝
I'm at their mercy now
相信我我是不得已 让我替魏家再办一件事
Trust me, I'll do one last thing for the Ngais
再办一件事伤天害理的事
What is it? Something illegal?
你不要多问 我自有分寸
Don't ask. I know what I'm doing
过了明天 我们马上回唐山
We'll return to Tang San the day after tomorrow
魏家的人打来了 快关门
They're here. Close the doors quickly
开门
Keep the doors open
把门打开
Open the doors
不准关门 我们百忍道场的人 没有一个是怕死的
Don't close the doors, we're no cowards.
对 我不怕死
We're no cowards
魏家人公然找上门来简直目无王法
The Ngais really have no respect for us
爹跟他们讲理也讲不通 我们跟他们拼了
There's no point reasoning with them. Let's take them on
师父 他们的人来啦
Sifu, they're here
来啦
Let's go
你们守外面许进不许出 出来一个杀一个
Guard the area and kill anyone that's not our own
是
Yes, sir.
大家分开
Move it
魏苍龙你带这么多人到这里来 到底想怎么样
Ngai, you've brought an army here. What do you want?
姓钟的 你不是叫我兄弟带信来跟我算账吗 我送上门来啦
Chung, didn't you say you wanted to get even with me? Here I am.
你不要这么神气 你平日所作所为你心里有数
You're despicable You should know what wrongs you've done
我当然有数啦 我杀人放火走私贩毒
Of course Murder, arson. Drugs. I've done them all
你能拿我怎么样 你有证据吗
What can you do? Any evidence?
你这种人作恶多端 迟早有报应
You'll pay for your crimes sooner or later
现在该我跟你算账了 你把许胖子抓了来 人在哪里
But now it's your turn to pay for your crime You detained Fatty Hui. Where is he now?
不知道
I don't know.
You don't know?
我看你是交不出人来啦
You can't hand him over?
唐浩云 找他要人
Tang How Yuen. Go ask him
钟老伯 我先跟你告个罪
Senior Chung, I apologise in advance
唐浩云 我对你很失望
Tang How Yuen. I'm very disappointed in you
我以为你是一个好汉 怎知道你为虎作伥
I thought you were a good man I would never have guessed you were a criminal
我受人之禄忠人之事 请你把人交出来
I'm only doing my job. Please hand over our man
人
Your man?
人是我抓回来的 没那么容易交出来
I arrested your man for a reason. I won't just hand him over
两国交兵各为其主 要是你再不交人我就不客气了
We both have our reasons for this encounter Hand over my man or face the consequences
你真以为你武功好 我们百忍道场的人怕你吗
Do you think you can intimidate us because your Kung Fu's good?
我不想伤和气 只要你们交人
I don't want to resort to violence. Just hand over our man
我们一定不交了
What if we refuse?
你听着 抓了我的人不放 还理直气壮
We've the right to ask for our man back. You shouldn't push your luck
要是你们不放人 魏家就没有错
The Ngais have the right to ask for their man back
那就算我 错就错到底
Come and get him, then
老大 你看出来没有 唐浩云手下留情啊
Big Bro, have you noticed? Tang How Yuen is being lenient on them
我看我们该下最后一步棋了吧
We've got to resort to plan B now.
师父
Sifu.
师父助你一腿
Let me help you
上
Attack
就用三弹腿打他
Give it to him
给我上
How Yuen. Your turn
小三子 你还不露馅
Sun. Show your true self now
爹
Dad Dad! Dad!
你伤得怎么样
Chung, are you OK?
他暗算我
I've been tricked
这是你做梦也想不到的吧
You'd never have guessed, right?
原来你是魏家的卧底
So you're working as an informer for the Ngais
我等了多少年才等到今天
I've waited a few years for this day
我一直待你不错 你这狼心狗肺的东西
I've treated you very well. You're no better than an animal
你骂我有什么用 只能怪你自己有眼无珠
There's no use scolding me now. Blame yourself for being so naive
我只有杀了你 才能报魏大爷对我的救命之恩
The only way I can repay Ngai for saving me, is with your life
老实告诉你 小喜子是我故意引出去害死的
To be honest, Kiddo's death was part of my plan too
你为什么要赖在我身上
Why did you make me the scapegoat?
我要造成你们的误会 加深你们的仇恨
I wanted to make your misunderstanding with Chung even worse
你有冤洗不清 你才会为魏大爷卖命啊
so you'd work for the Ngais more diligently
对了 这都是我的奇谋妙计啊
That's right, we planned all this right from the start
我再告诉你 许胖子还是我叫小三子抓去
I'll tell you something, it's me who asked Sun to capture Fatty Hui
再把他杀死灭口
We killed him too
他是你们魏家的人 为什么要这么做
He's the Ngai's man too. Why did you kill him?
牺牲几个人算得了什么呢
Sacrificing a life is nothing to us
许胖子死在百忍道场 才使我们师出有名啊
Because Fatty Hui died in Patience Clan's custody we can hold them to account.
唐浩云
Tang How Yuen
现在只剩三个人
There are three of them left,
你把他们打死 百忍道场就没有了
kill them and Patience Clan will cease to exist
那么你的任务也完了
Your responsibility will also end here
你们这帮人真下流无耻 唐浩云不为你用
You're despicable I won't be exploited by you
你忘了我们昨天 是怎么讲定的
Don't forget what we agreed yesterday
你不讲信用 你不想回唐山了
If you don't keep your promise, you'll never get back to Tang San
对畜生没有信用这两个字
What does an animal like you know about promises?
你不听我的命令
You know what
你该知道我怎么对付你
I'll do if you don't do what I say
你们想怎么对付我 不怕死的上来
What can you do? Is anyone brave enough to take me on now?
我告诉你们 有我唐浩云在
With me here,
谁都不准动姓钟的
no one shall touch Senior Chung
小唐啊 你别以为你了不起 你是常山赵子龙打不死…
Young man. Don't be so arrogant You think you're invincible?
真他妈的
What the...?
住手
Look
魏苍龙 你
Ngai Chong Loong!
现在两个人在我手里 你要考虑清楚
They're both in my hands Act carefully
我老实告诉你 你师娘根本没有病 是我下了毒
To be honest, your Simo wasn't ill I poisoned her
你把他们三个人打死 我就给你解药 放你回唐山
Kill the three of them and I'll give you the antidote
我们的事一了百了
We'll call it quits when you're back in Tang San
这也是我的锦囊妙计 是我派小三子去下的毒
That was one of my great ideas too I had Sun lace the tea with poison
你要是不听我大哥的命令
If you don't do what Big Bro says
你师娘非疼死不可 我看你还是听话的好
your Simo will die a painful death Just be obedient
你要是不听我的话 只要我一举手
Don't think about it for long. I just need to give the sign
这两条命就没有了
and it'll be the end of them
浩云 你怎么一直瞒着我 你怎么会跟这种坏人做事
How Yuen. Why did you keep this from me? Why did you work for these people?
我 我…
I...
姓魏的 你不要逼他
Ngai Chong Loong, there's no point forcing him
浩云 你师父一生忠义
How Yuen. Your Sifu was a righteous man
假如你帮人为非作歹 他会死不瞑目
If he knew what you were doing now, he'd turn in his grave
不要管我 为了唐山门的名誉着想 好好的照顾师妹
Do it for me and for the good name of Tang San Clan Take good care of your Lan
妈
Mum, Mum!
师娘
Simo!
你这个畜生 我打死你
You, animal! Die!
接住
Die!
走 走
Let's go.  Let's go
师哥
Brother
师娘 妈
- Simo! - Mum!